## **Grey Hardy**

(678) 743-1785 | greyhardy7@gmail.com Github | LinkedIn | Portfolio

# **Data Analytics & Science**

Data Manager experienced in Microsoft SQL database management, ETL, Python, Tableau, business intelligence, data visualization, EDA, and machine learning. Strong analytical and technical skills that provide data insights to solve business problems with clarity.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Python, R, Excel, VBA

Kits: Matplotlib, NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Seaborn, Sklearn, Keras

Applications/Engines: Jupyter Notebook, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQL, Visual Studio, Anaconda, GitHub

Visualization: Tableau, PowerBI

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### Diabetic Hospital Readmissions Prediction - Link O

Built an interactive application that predicts hospital readmissions of diabetic patients within 30 days using a random forest classification model.

- Performed ETL process, split the data into training and test sets, Normalized with StandardScaler, and utilized SMOTE to address imbalance data. Random Forest provided the best performance
- Built a website using HTML, Bootstrap, CSS and published and Heroku app

### NYC Citi Bike Visualization - Link O Tableau Story

- Designed NYC Citi Bike visualization of interactive bike stations utilizing across the city using HTML, d3, CSS, API, Leaflet, JavaScript
- Built Tableau dashboard to provide insights examining the rider duration, type, statical analyst, and preferences.

### Cryptocurrency Analysis – Link O

Utilized unsupervised machine learning to create a report of cryptocurrencies on the trading market, grouped then to create a classification system to be used for a future investment portfolio by the client.

- Performed dimensional reduction with PCA. Preserved 90% of the explained variance further reduced the dataset with t-SNE and created a scatterplot of the output.
- Elbow plot was used to identify the Cryptocurrency clustering providing 5 classifications for the portfolio

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Manager, Enterprise Applications, Cox Enterprises, Atlanta, GA

10/2017 - Present

- Reduced technical debt consolidated multiple SQL clustered environments
- Completed Control-M platform upgrade ahead of schedule, \$25,000 cost savings
- Utilized data mining and produced visualization dashboard to support staffing model to meet SLAs
- Provide a consistent and seamless user experience enterprise-wide to improve customer interactions and simplify the helpdesk process
- Vendor management contract negotiations, annual budget (\$500K), strategic alignment, and performance measurement
- Experience leading organizations up to 13 people, across multiple countries, while supporting significant numbers of clients and projects.

Problem Manager, Cox Automotive, Atlanta, GA

1/2015 - 10/2017

- Reduced service outages by creating dashboards to monitor product failures, estimated saving of \$350,000+
- Established governance process with business and technology executives to align on strategy, decisions and measure success through KPIs
- Led Inclusion & Diversity team through design-thinking process; empathy, define, and ideation phases founding enterprise-wide employee resource group

- Expand trustworthy partnerships with business leaders across divisions to deliver strategic solutions that drive transformation, improve productivity, and streamline business operations
- Mature ITIL service operation processes, lead change management, communication, and policies to effectively run the IT Operations organization

### **INCLUSION LEADERSHIP**

Founding Co-Chair Employee Resource Group, Cox Automotive, Atlanta, GA

B.S. in Mass Communication, Minor in Electronic Mass Media

12/2016 - 10/2017

- Led Inclusion & Diversity team through the design-thinking process; empathy, define, and ideation phases founding enterprisewide employee resource group
- Established leadership team, set strategy, objectives, and KPI's combined business strategies with inclusion and diversity initiatives
- Influenced expansion of health care benefits coverage for the transgender workforce
- Gained DiverstiyInc, Forbes Best Employers for Diversity, and Human Rights Campaign Best Places to work status

Inaugural Award Recipient, Business Person of the Year, Georgia Out Business Alliance, Atlanta, GA	8/2018
EDUCATION	
Georgia Tech, Atlanta, GA	12/2021
Data Analytics and Science Bootcamp program, 4.0 GPA	
Ashford University, San Diego, CA	04/2019
Executive M.B.A, Organizational Leadership, 4.0 GPA	
Brenau University, Gainesville, GA	12/1997

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

ITIL V3, VMware VCP5-DCV & VCA-DCV, Microsoft MCSA 2012, and Certified Helpdesk Manager.